Inventory of the Smith-Walker Papers 1764-1916
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, College of William and Mary
Smith-Walker Papers, 1764-1916.
Special Collections, College of William and Mary
Mss. 39.1 Sm8
3,098 items.
The Smith-Walker Papers include business and personal letters, accounts and legal documents, chiefly 1860-1900, of members of the Smith family of Smith's Crossroads, Mecklenburg County, Virginia and the Walker family of Brunswick County, Virginia.
Smith Family,; Walker Family,; Thomas W. Smith.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Purchased: 3,098 items 02/23/1939.
Scope and Content Information
This collection of 3,098 pieces, dated about 1764-1916, consists of papers of a family of Smiths who lived at Smith's Cross Roads, Mecklenburg County, Virginia, and the Walker family who lived at Brunswick County, Virginia. Most of the papers are dated about 1860-1900. Some of the more interesting works include the following:
A letter concerning news of the State Legislature (Va.), amending laws regarding transporting slaves across state lines, dated 28 Dec. 1806.
A personal letter from J. J. Grigg to Edward Walker about his school at Sturgeonville, Va., dated 1 Jan. 1840.
A "religious exhortation" from Jas. D. Coultris [?] to Edw. Walker concerning his "wil practices" and his keeping of the Sabbath, dated 19 Feb. 1844.
Many recipes are also mentioned. They are located in box: 1, folder: 3, and include the following: "Cure for Colic in Horse" and "Dr. Blair's Cure for Dysentery"; boiled bread pudding, raspberry jam, tomato catsup, worcester sauce, citron preserves, boiled icing, jelly puddings, dried apple pies, sweet pickle peaches, tomato jelly, brown bread, German pickle cantaloupe, cabbage sauce, cabbage slaw, domestic wine, and blackberry wine.
Arrangement
Organization
This collection has been organized into six Series: 1. Letters; 2. Other Writings; 3. Account, Receipts, Legal Papers, Etc.; 4. Bound Account Books; 5. Broadsides, Order Forms, Advertisements, Etc.; 6. Miscellaneous Printed Matter.
Arrangement
Materials in this collection are separated into Series and then arranged chronological by date. In Series 2, the items are then also separated by surname.
Index Terms
Family Names:
Smith Family; Walker Family
Geographical Names:
Mecklenburg County (Va.)-- History--19th century.; Brunswick County (Va.)-- History--19th century.
Components List
  Series 1: Letters
- Letters, 1803-1914.
  - Letter by individuals with the following surnames: Davis, Ferress, Mathews, Smith, Walker, etc., 1803-1879. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Letters by individuals with the following surnames: Walker, King, etc., 1880-1914, n.d. (Box-folder 1:2)
  Series 2: Other Writings
- Other Writings. (Box-folder 1:3)
  Poetry essays, recipes, and sermon notes.
  Series 3:Accounts, Receipts, Legal Papers, Etc.
- Accounts, Receipts, Legal Papers, Etc., ca. 1700-1916, n.d.
  This series includes items pertaining to individuals with the following surnames:
  - Mathews (Mathis), Walker; 17__-1790. (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Mathews Mathis, Walker; 1791-1797. (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Mathews, Walker, etc.; 1798-1799. (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Walker, Mathews, etc.; 1800-1802. (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Walker, Mathews, etc.; 1803-1806. (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Walker, Mathews, Baskervill[e]; 1807-1809. (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Walker, Mathews; 1810. (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Walker, Mathews, Jarrat; 1811. (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Walker, Mathews; 1812. (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Walker, Mathews; 1813-1814. (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Walker, Mathews; 1815-1816. (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Walker, etc.; 1817. (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Walker, Mathews, Baskervill[e]; 1818. (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Walker, Baskervill[e], Rogers, Dortch, etc.; 1819. (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Walker, Baskervill[e], Dortch, Evans; 1820. (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Walker, Baskervill[e], Dortch, Evans; 1821. (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Walker, Baskervill[e], Dortch, Evans; 1822. (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Walker; 1823-1825. (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Walker, Bennett, Baskervill[e], Thomas; 1826-1827. (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Walker, Baskervill[e], Bennett; 1828. (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Walker, Baskervill[e], Davis; 1829. (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Walker, Warren, Crutchfield, Davis, Oslin, Harwell; 1830. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Walker, Crichton, etc.; 1831. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Walker, Dortch, Tanner, Baskervill[e]; 1832. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Walker, Ezell, Baskervill[e], Dortch, Bridg[e]forth; 1833. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Walker, Baskervill[e], Dortch, Bridg[e]forth, Bennett; 1834. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Walker, Smith, Dortch, Bridg[e]forth; 1835-1836. (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Walker, Cleaton, Dortch, Bridg[e]forth, "Baskervill[e] & Bacon;" 1837. (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Walker, Farrar, Ezell; 1838. (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Walker, Cleaton, Ezell, Evans, Taylor, Tanner, Farrar, Boyd, Thomas, Baskervill[e]; 1839. (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Walker, Thomas, Evans, Hatchel, Dortch, etc.; 1840. (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Walker, Evans; 1841. (Box-folder 2:11)
  - Walker, Evans; 1842. (Box-folder 2:12)
  - Walker; 1843. (Box-folder 2:13)
  - Walker; 1844. (Box-folder 2:14)
  - Walker, Evans, Tanner, Smith; 1845. (Box-folder 2:15)
  - Walker, Green, Dugger; 1846. (Box-folder 2:16)
  - Walker, Green; 1847. (Box-folder 2:17)
  - Walker, Ezell; 1848. (Box-folder 2:18)
  - Walker, Tanner; 1849. (Box-folder 2:19)
  - Walker, Cleaton, Tanner; 1850-1851. (Box-folder 2:20)
  - Walker, Tanner; 1852. (Box-folder 2:21)
  - Walker, Evans, Tanner; 1853. (Box-folder 2:22)
  - Walker, Tanner; 1854-1856. (Box-folder 2:23)
  - Walker, Tanner, Evans, Williams; 1857-1859. (Box-folder 2:24)
  - Walker, Evans, Cleaton, Ezell, Smith; 1860-1863. (Box-folder 2:25)
  - Walker, Evans, Tanner; 1864-1867. (Box-folder 2:26)
  - Walker, Evans, Tanner; 1868. (Box-folder 2:27)
  - Evans, Walker, Moss; 1869. (Box-folder 2:28)
  - Evans, Walker, Smith, Tanner, Moss, Taylor; 1870-1872. (Box-folder 2:29)
  - Walker, Evans, Tanner, Bennett (estate); 1873-1875. (Box-folder 2:30)
  - Smith, Bennett, Walker, Tanner, Lett; 1876. (Box-folder 2:31)
  - Walker, Smith, Lett; 1877. (Box-folder 2:32)
  - Smith, Baskervill[e], Hayes, Bennett, Walker; 1878. (Box-folder 2:33)
  - Walker, Smith; 1879 (Box-folder 2:34)
  - Smith, Davis, Cook, Bennett, Walker, Mathews; 1880-1881. (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Walker, Smith; 1882. (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Smith, Bennett, Baskervill[e], Walker; 1883. (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Walker, Smith, Mathews; 1884. (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Smith, Mathews, Whittle, Butterworth, Davis; 1885. (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Smith, Davis, Tanner, Walker, Mathews, Evans; 1886. (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Smith, Ryland, Evans; 1887. (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Smith, Walker, Harris; 1888-1889. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Walker, Smith, Lyon, Ryland; 1890. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Smith, Walker, Baskervill[e]; 1891. (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Smith, Walker, Tanner, Alexander; 1892 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - Smith, Alexander, Watkins, Bowen, Lyon; 1893. (Box-folder 3:12)
  - Smith, Spragins, Bowen, Rainey, Dugger; 1894. (Box-folder 3:13)
  - Smith, Spragins, Hagood, Tillman, Ryland, Walker, Bracey; 1895. (Box-folder 3:14)
  - Smith, Spragins, Ryland; 1896-1899. (Box-folder 3:15)
  - Smith, Holloway; 1900-1902. (Box-folder 3:16)
  - Smith, Taylor, Baskervill[e]; 1903-1905. (Box-folder 3:17)
  - Smith; 1906. (Box-folder 3:18)
  - Smith, Taylor, Dugger, Baskervill[e], Davis; 1907. (Box-folder 3:19)
  - Smith, Baskervill[e]; 1908. (Box-folder 3:20)
  - Smith, Baskervill[e]; 1909. (Box-folder 3:21)
  - Smith, Baskervill[e]; 1910-1911. (Box-folder 3:22)
  - Smith, Mayo; 1912. (Box-folder 3:23)
  - Smith, Mayo; 1913. (Box-folder 3:24)
  - Smith, Walker; 1914-1916. (Box-folder 3:25)
  - Mixed names as above; n.d. (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Mixed names as above; n.d. (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Mixed names as above; n.d. (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Items that were torn or separated from others list above; n.d. (Box-folder 4:4)
  Series 4: Bound Account Books
- Bound Account Books; ca. 1837 -1910. (Box 4)
  - Small leather bound account book belonging to Edward Walker; ca. 1837. (Box 4)
  - Larger paper bound account book belonging to Smith?; 1899-1910. (Box 4)
  Series 5: Broadsides, Order Forms, Advertisements, Etc.
- Broadsides, Order Forms, Advertisements, Etc. (Box-folder 5:1-3)
  Series 6: Miscellaneous Printed Matter
- Miscellaneous Printed Matter, ca. 1880-1890., Items loose in box 5. (Box 5)
  Items include memo books, calender books, and trade lists.